mission critical: 

"Production":  If it goes down at 3am, I have to get out of bed.

"Mission Critical":  If it goes down at 3am, EVERYONE gets out of bed.
..
We eliminated a lot of pseudo-"production" boxes by making a policy,
"if its a production machine, it needs to be on a server-form-factor
system in the datacenter, not on a tower under your desk."
 - Bill Bradford


To me, mission critical means the host has a rocket/spaceship attached.
Because rockets and space are cool, and that's a real mission. None of
this counting money stuff.
 - Ethan O'Toole